1-script.com 2012-05-23

# Privacy Policy - Web Development Blog

**Privacy Policy for 1-Script.com**

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by visiting our [contact form page ](http://www.1-script.com/site/contact/ "1-Script.com Contact Page")

At _1-Script.com_ , the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines what type of personal information is collected and stored by _1-Script.com_ and how it is used.

**Website Visitors**  
Like most website operators, _1-Script.com_ collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. _1-Script.com_ ’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how _1-Script.com_ ’s visitors use its website. From time to time, _1-Script.com_ may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

_1-Script.com_ also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on _1-Script.com_ blog and forums. _1-Script.com_ only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**  
Certain visitors to _1-Script.com_ ’s websites choose to interact with _1-Script.com_ in ways that require _1-Script.com_ to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that _1-Script.com_ gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a blog for forum user account at _1-Script.com_ to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with _1-Script.com_ – by purchasing a product or service, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, _1-Script.com_ collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with _1-Script.com_. _1-Script.com_ does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Aggregated Statistics**  
_1-Script.com_ may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. _1-Script.com_ may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, _1-Script.com_ does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**  
_1-Script.com_ discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on _1-Script.com_ ’s behalf or to provide services available at _1-Script.com_ ’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using _1-Script.com_ ’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. _1-Script.com_ will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, _1-Script.com_ discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when _1-Script.com_ believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of _1-Script.com_ , third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an _1-Script.com_ website and have supplied your email address, _1-Script.com_ may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with _1-Script.com_ and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. _1-Script.com_ takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. _1-Script.com_ uses cookies to help _1-Script.com_ identify and track visitors, their usage of _1-Script.com_ website, and their website access preferences. _1-Script.com_ visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using _1-Script.com_ ’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of _1-Script.com_ ’s website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Business Transfers**  
If _1-Script.com_ , or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that _1-Script.com_ goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquiror of _1-Script.com_ may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

**Ads**  
Some pages of this site may carry on-line advertisements in various forms ( **“ads”** ). Ads appearing on our website may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by _1-Script.com_ and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**  
.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on 1-Script.com.  
.:: Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to 1-Script.com and other sites on the Internet.  
.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include ….

  * Google Adsense
  * Chitika

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send the advertisements and links that appear on _1-Script.com_ directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

_1-Script.com_ has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. _1-Script.com_ ‘s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

  * To opt out of Google Ads cookies, please visit this page at Google website: <http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/>
  * To opt out of Chitika Ads cookies, please visit this page at Chitika website: <http://chitika.com/privacy>

**Privacy Policy Changes**  
Although most changes are likely to be minor, _1-Script.com_ may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in _1-Script.com_ ’s sole discretion. _1-Script.com_ encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

_This document was last updated on November 4th, 2011_
